## Harry Staley

Harry Staley is a life-long learner with a love for data and the democratization of information that has come to the world with the advent of the Internet. His passion for technology began in 2004 with the development of a database project during a summer internship while working on his first Bachelor's Degree. Since that time, he has grown that passion for technology and for how data fuels the engine of modern innovations such as IDS, voice assistants, and autonomous vehicles. Through his journey he has engaged in self-directed learning using tools like MIT Open Courseware, Khan Academy, and Coursera to grow his toolkit of skills and knowledge, and now gives back to others by teaching Python and Cyber Security through Udacity and ThriveDX.

As part of Harry's vision for the democratization of information online, he engages in community volunteer efforts working on open source software, working with organizations like Code Alliance and Techtonica, and mentoring students. For the last 12 years, Harry has applied his skills in data science and data engineering to serve the public through advancing the efficiency of US Army & DoD procurement systems.

# **Experience**

#### U.S. Army Civilian Service | May 2011 - Present

Interim Data Team Lead, Data Scientist (ORSA) | ODASA(P) | May 2021 - Present

- Delivered decision support tools for senior executive leadership with global scope.
- Developed a cross-functional architectural diagram documenting the data pipeline from the point of collection to data warehousing and arrival at analytics platforms.
- Championed Agile methodologies as a best practice to foster a culture of continuous delivery to achieve mission objectives.
- Constructed a data team charter aligned to strategic lines of effort.
- Cultivated cross-functional relationships with data owners across the DoD to acquire new data sources.
- Collaborated with senior Data Scientists to develop an enterprise solution to track acquisitions in support of the conflict in Ukraine before the addition of a National Interest Action (NIA) code.
- Co-leading the Army Data Science Community of Interest.

#### Team Member - Acquisition Innovation Through Technology | ODASA(P) | Oct 2020 - Apr 2021

- Developed business cases to apply new and emerging technologies such as machine learning, artificial intelligence, and robotic process automation to existing acquisition processes.
- Led the project to provide an enterprise analytics capability for the Armys' Government Purchase Card program.
- Conducted research and evaluated technologies to bring structure to unstructured data.
- Worked with data owners to procure new data sources for enterprise analytics to use.

#### Procurement Systems Analyst, Business Intelligence | MICC | May 2011 - May 2021

- Delivered decision support tools for executive leadership with US wide scope.
- Developed analytics tools to analyze the largest and most complex Government Purchase Card program in the Army.
  - Awarded the Civilian Service Achievement Medal for this project.
- · Mentored ORSA team members on computer science concepts.
- · Regularly briefed senior leaders as a metrics champion.
- Change control board member for several procurement systems.

#### Lead Instructor | ThriveDX | Sep 2021 - Present

- Promoted from Associate to Lead in April 2022
- Teaching for several colleges/universities in a highly interactive style to distill technical topics for learners.
- Responsible for classroom management, pedagogy, scaffolded learning, and understanding checks.
- Focused on building career ready cybersecurity and Python software development professionals.

Full Stack Web Developer (Freelance) | CraftedTech | Aug 2016 - Oct 2021

Computer Science and Math Tutor | Parliament Tutors | Aug 2019 - Apr 2022

Project Reviewer & Mentor | Udacity | Aug 2016 - Sep 2018

- Reviewed and adjudicated project submissions based on project rubrics.
- Provided constructive feedback on project submissions.
- Mentored students as they implemented their projects.

Research Assistant | Texas A&M University-San Antonio - Cybersecurity | Nov 2017 - May 2018

- Identified additional research that could help minimize attack vectors in secure clouds.
- Assisted with research on "Risk-aware Multi-Objectives Optimized Virtual Machine Placement in Cloud" under a grant from the Army Research Office.

Full Stack Web Developer (Volunteer) | Benetech - Code Alliance | Aug 2016 - Dec 2017

- Technical Lead on a high-impact volunteer project helping develop a mature web prototype for Benetech labs.
- Improved web presence of Techtonica.org through the use of Python Flask & Jinja templating.

Business Intelligence Developer (Internship) | USAA | May 2017 - Aug 2017

Software Engineer / Data Analytics Consultant | Scholastic | Jun 2009 - Jan 2011

## **Education**

MS, Computer Science | Georgia Institute of Technology | 2022-Present

BS, Computer Science (Summa Cum Laude) | Texas A&M University-San Antonio | 2019

AS, Computer Science/Mathematics (Summa Cum Laude) | St. Phillips College | 2017

AAS, Business and Marketing | Ozarks Technical Community College | 2009

### **Publications**

A Practice of Detecting Insider Threats within a Network Advances in Security, Networks, and the Internet of Things | Feb 2021

### **Certifications**

DAWIA Engineering & Technical Management (Practitioner) | Feb 2022

CompTIA Security+ | License COMP001003566872 | Aug 2019

CompTIA Network+ | License COMP001003566872 | July 2006

# **Security Clearance**

SECRET | ACTIVE | Adjudicated Oct. 2015

## **Honors and Awards**

- Star Note from DASA(P)
- · Certificate of Appreciation from Gen. Christine Beeler
- Civilian Service Achievement Medal
- Achievement Medal for Civilian Service x 2
- Challenge Coin from the ASA(ALT)

staleyh@gmail.com | +1 (330) 718-1876 | 8884 Staghorn Mill, Converse, TX 78109